I don't have that mental block of like,
oh I got to meet with my boss and
explain the things I've done this week
because I'm responsible for them. No, I
it's me it's me and me. Oh, let me call
my boss. Can I get the day off? Yep,
you're off today, right?
That's the truth of it, right?
When I make plans, I do this with my
friends. I can you go can you do this on
Friday?
My buddies are we're hanging out like,
hey, can you message your can you tell
us if you can do this on Friday? I go,
hey, can you get today off? Oh, wait, I
have Friday off now. Okay, cool. I did
say I was off.
All right, man. Ben, thanks for thanks
for coming on the pod, dude. We had a
little bit of a pre-chat right before
this episode and we realized we were
getting lost in the conversation and we
said, oh, we got to we got to start the
pod. Um I think it's a good time to
start it, yeah, for sure.
Yeah, exactly.
So
dude, so excited to have you on the pod.
We've been saving you actually, you
know, cuz when we launched the podcast,
we were like, hey, you know, could we
have you on the pod and then we
realized, hey, let's get a little bit of
traction first. Let's get our our
training wheels off and then we'll we're
ready for the big guns. So I think we're
here. I think we're ready to roll and um
I don't know if I'd like to be called
the big gun. I feel like you guys are
putting expectation all the way up here
and then I hope I deliver for it, but
Yeah. I appreciate it. I hope I can live
up to the expectations, too. Well,
that's good. I think it's a it's a
shared responsibility, but you know, we
we like to keep the pressure on.
So in line with that, I I think we're
going to go ahead and start off the
episode
um with a little little story. Uh and
we're going to flashback to 2022. Um
this is a
sort of a memory I have
of us sitting together at a table at a
hotel in Colorado at a HackerOne live
hacking event. And I think this was a
pretty rough time period in your life
and you were you and I were
collaborating together and talking about
you know, how to approach this target
and you were feeling a lot of
insecurity and not confidence in the bug
bounty journey, which is kind of crazy
to me because I I you know, got into bug
bounty watching your videos and seeing
your content. And so I was glad to be
able to be there for that time. But then
I look back at that that and then I look
at now, which is you know, years later
having just done a 500k year in bug
bounty and I just wonder about that
journey. So I was wondering if you could
take us back to that spot and then bring
us forward to today.
Yeah, so I mean the table you were
talking about it was me so me and you
and I were working on some projects in
the past
non-hacking related and then I kind of I
ghosted you and I
got in person like, okay, I owe this guy
an apology. So I said, hey, like sorry I
have to ghost you guys and you know,
there was context to it and I think
at the time I was actually on the come
out of that entire problem, you know, so
I a lot of people know this I I was
married for a while and uh before COVID
happened, I was you know, really
struggling with like depression,
anxiety,
a lot of different issues and then in
2020 I went through a divorce and
actually like Joel, I think was one of
the first people that found out about
the the breakup. It was just uh I think
I found out about some stuff in his life
and then I messaged him like, hey, I
heard you were going through some stuff
and Christmas is coming up. What are you
doing? He was like, oh, I'm not going
back home. I'm going to be you know, in
my area. I was like, do you want to come
hang out with me? We can just hang out
and I got I just got a puppy. You want
to come meet my new dog? And uh he came
up and uh
funny enough we put some furniture
together that we broke and then I sent
it back to the
We don't have to talk about that, but
yeah, um I think before I can talk about
that though,
um there is a little bit to talk about
the
what got me to 2022 where you and I sat
at that table.
I kind of told you about it, right?
So about um
2018, I want to say 2018, 2019 is when I
got into content creation. I started
with with my live stream. This is when
like the first live recon happened.
I didn't have this beautiful office. I
had a bunch of like people in the
background because yeah, it was
but Getting banned from Twitch. Getting
banned from Twitch, yeah, a lot of like
different crazy stuff that happened and
you know, the the big thing with you
know, that I also applaud you guys for
doing this the consistency when it comes
down to creating content. You guys are
you know, pushing out a
podcast once a week. You're doing these
calls. I just saw you guys doing a prep
call, you know, before the podcast. I'm
sure you guys spend hours before it. I
want to say for every hour of content
that you're making, you're putting into
about five hours of work at least
minimum, right? So now imagine that I'm
doing four days of streams a week. I was
streaming Friday, Saturday, Sunday and
Monday. No way. And this is this is this
is before we were stuck this is before
we were told we have to stay at home on
Friday, Saturday, Sundays because of
COVID, right? So I wasn't going out on
Fridays in the morning. I wasn't going
out Friday nights because I had to
stream on Saturdays. I wasn't going out
Saturday nights because I had to stream
on Sundays and I couldn't go and do
stuff with family on Sunday mornings
about to stream.
And when you do that and you're away
from family, you're away from doing the
things that you love and you have family
members around you that miss you,
friends that don't see you. Everyone was
like, oh, we can't see you this weekend
because you have to stream, right? That
was the go-to with me. So I built up a
lot of like pressure on external
people in my life that they wanted to
see me and I couldn't see them. So that
put so much a lot of pressure. I
couldn't travel anymore. There's all
these things, right? So I want to I want
to pause it and go ahead, Joel. Yeah,
well we both have so many questions
about this.
at a time. One at a time.
SO I WAS I WAS GOING to say I have a
friend
who I know personally. He
was not a streamer and he transitioned
into now full-time streaming. He's been
doing it for about a year. And I've
noticed this. I don't know how much it's
affected him, but I was curious like
what it felt like in the moment
for you because I think like in the
moment it's very easy to just sort of be
like, I'm growing, like things are going
really well for this. I'm putting a lot
of time and effort into this. Like it's
working. I'm just going to keep doing
that. And it's kind of easy to sort of
justify the reasons for why the other
aspects of your life sort of start to
fall apart. Um what was it like like
from your perspective like going into
like in hindsight it's easy to see. Like
you know, okay, I'm spending too much
time and and energy on that. I probably
should have focused on family, but like
in the moment what was it what was it
like from the inside?
Um so the thing with me is I have a very
addictive personality that I can
control. I can't control when it comes
down to like the things that I enjoy
doing. Like I can control when it comes
to like drinking and partying and
things. I can control that part. But
when it comes down to like hacking, you
know, when you get that high of like
success that you're getting whether it's
content, bug bounties, whatever it is
I'm doing, that is the time that I can't
control at all. So at first it was bug
bounties, you know, I was you know, I
was working full-time. I was doing bug
bounties and then I took a break. I was
like, okay, now I want to do content.
But when you're hitting success to this,
hard to say no. It's hard to take a
break.
Yeah.
Because you know,
with with hacking the thing that I
really struggled with was every time I
went out to hang out with my friends,
that was you know, six hours of going
out and then if I went out drinking,
three hours of being hungover in the
morning. That's about a nine hour of
time that I lost where I could have been
making bounties, right? Now if I'm
streaming every day, if I miss one day,
people dude, people are quick to forget
you when you stop making content.
Yeah.
I've you know, it's very hard to say no
to doing things and that's just one
aspect of content that I've just talked
about. There's more to you know, how it
changes your life, but just from a
perspective of like success, it is
really hard to say no when your when
your growth is like it's not even like
slowly going up. It was a huge I had a
huge growth with Twitch. I think I got
like 10 to 15,000 followers within a
couple with a year. Wow. And I had a
huge community. I would tweet out, you
know, random [__] on Twitter and it
would get a lot of attention and I was
just like, holy crap, this is becoming
real. Like people actually like
And with dude, Twitch has one of the
most engaged communities. It is insane
how people can you know, support you,
how they interact with you. They want to
like be a part of your community. I've
never seen it like that. And then when
you come into that, it's just hard to
give up. It's hard to like let go,
right? Um so just you know, taking a
pause, you know, there was times that I
would take a like HackerOne would say,
hey, we're doing the H1415 for example,
you got to come to San Francisco. I
would take a weekend off, but the whole
time in my mind I'm going, please don't
drop my numbers when I go back next
week. Please you know, I hope my
regulars come back. I hope my regular
viewers come back or at least I get the
engagement. Yeah.
really hard to say no to it, but the
other thing that comes with content
when you're doing streams is you're
showing the authentic version of
yourself. You cannot hide who you are
when you're doing a stream. And that
comes when you're doing technical
content, it's harder. When I don't know
a topic on stream, guess what? I'm going
to look it up. Those mistakes you made
that you're not you're inefficient,
everybody sees it and everybody judges
you. That's what people say, do you
don't want to meet your heroes. Well,
it's And I don't want to meet my hero.
It's vulnerable, too. You know, you like
you're going on there and you know that
that's going to happen time and time
again. All of us know, even the pros
that we have to you know, still Google
how to write a markdown link or like,
you know, get the syntax right and
specific things. So People don't see it
that way. People thought, you know, I
was getting some some top hackers were
like very disappointed in how I was
doing things on streams. I had messages
of people that I call these elite
hackers that I distance myself nowadays
that they're like, oh, you this is how
you do it. You didn't know how to do it
on the stream. And I was like, no, I I
kind of know how to do it, but it's like
I'm also teaching things to people. So I
was doing a lot of like
things in a Google sheet for example
because you know, people that was the
early days and I didn't want to jump
into bash right away and then people
were like, oh, you don't know how to do
basic stuff and I'm like, which one is
it? Do I teach people or do I come up
and be the super elite hacker that knows
everything, right? Even if even if you
do it a different way, that's a part of
Even if you don't I mean, even if you do
it a different way, that's a part of
your unique hacker identity, too, you
know, there's no there's no reason why
somebody needs to come and say like,
hey, you don't know like literally
everything about bash. What's wrong with
you? Because you know, that knowledge
that they spent getting, you know,
learning bash, you've spent somewhere
else, right? And and then you've got
that that sort of knowledge trade-off on
the other side.
And so it's never never a good idea. You
never like to see people shame
other hackers for you know lack of
knowledge in some in some areas cuz you
never know where that knowledge got
traded to.
Yeah. I want to answer your original
question. Go ahead, Joe.
Well, well, this with this actually that
we had a great discussion about this
recently
and Reza brought up this XKCD called
I think it's like 1 in 10,000 or
something. And it's basically like it's
basically I don't know if this is how
real this
statistic is or whatever, but it's
basically that like every day like
10,000 adults like learn
something like for the first time
and
if somebody hasn't heard about something
for the first time, then they're they're
one in 10,000. Like that they're you
know, they're part of the statistic and
just like that's okay. Like that's going
to happen. You're going to be part of
that someday, too or you already have
been.
Um
I think the other aspect of it is like
there's so much emphasis that's put
nowadays on like being like a dictionary
of things and like
I can appreciate that to some extent,
but I also think it's equally important
to be able to like
use the resources around you to find
things without having to like know it
explicitly and that's like relying on
Google or like relying on your peers or
bookmarks or notes or whatever to like
help you find things so that you don't
have to cuz your brain can only hold so
much, right? Like you're going to you're
going to have to like start to exchange
some knowledge out for other things and
having systems that you can like find
that
And data in an efficient way is just as
important. And that's that's one of the
things that I think you did great on
those streams, Ben, was like equipping
people with the knowledge of how to go
and get the information, you know? Like
even even if you you know, like you were
just talking about, even if you don't
know off the top of your head, oh, what
is the syntax? Well, I'm just going to
open the man page. Well, some people
didn't know about man page and now that
you've just equipped them with that that
way. And as as a as a a mentor to a
couple young hackers, one of the things
I'm struggling with right now is how do
I embed in in them that confidence that
they can go find the technical piece of
information they need to solve their
problem,
you know, without relying on a mentor
and and that's one of the the best
things that that you know, you can do to
equip a mentee, I think. Um
But yeah, sorry. So we got a little off
topic. Going back to your question. The
number one the number one thing that I
got on my streams always was it makes me
feel good that a pro like this has to
look up the most basic concept and my
answer would be like that's how it's
supposed to be. Like that's how it's
supposed to be at all time, right? And
the people that tell you they don't look
things up and now I have people on my
streams when I do the interviews,
they're like, oh, I know this in the
back of my head. I'm like, cool. Like
you're just storing [__] in your back of
your brain that's you know, you're going
to use once a year. I applaud it, but it
you know, you learn things as you you do
it more and more, but I don't want to
jump into the I don't want to talk too
much about the content piece of it
because I know people want to do all
sorts of technical stuff, but Yeah. the
the biggest thing that I you know, I
came across this um
I came across this bit of a podcast. I I
wish I knew what podcast it was. I just
remember the message from it that it was
you know, when I was early in the days
of like creating this brand and you
know, the name or whatever you want to
call it was if you want to become a
online person, you're given two options.
Those two options are you either have to
um fully off yourself and unalive
yourself of who you are and create this
new persona and you know, be this new
person that you can
put up the charade if you want to call
it and become this person that you are
online and live it up, you know, every
day day in and day out when you're on
camera or you have to amplify the crap
out of crap out of who you are
personally and people are either going
to love you for it or they're going to
hate you for it and you have to be okay
with it. And I took the approach of just
being myself and you know, being okay
with being who I am and I know a lot of
people that don't like me for it and I
know a lot of people that have actually
enjoyed seeing me who I am, seen my
growth online and seen the things that I
do and that was the biggest change that
I I I applied and it helped a lot with
uh the personality, but I want to kind
of you know, I want to answer your
question about like what happened in
Denver, but I feel like we need to
understand the context of what was going
on 2018 to 2022 in my life where I had
no social life, I had no you know, my my
partner at the time was fed up with it
and I had issues with her at the time,
too and you know, I'm just not spending
any time with anybody because I want I
wanted it that enough, right? And then
get to 2022, COVID happens.
And you know, we're locked in now. I
hadn't seen my parents in 5 years. I was
supposed to see them. That's not
happening anymore. My brother had a kid.
I was supposed to go see the baby.
That's not happening anymore. We're
locked into the house and there's
nothing happening and on top of it, I'm
going through a divorce while everyone's
locked in in the house. So I that's the
reality of my life at the time and
Luckily that 2022 is like literally is
literally when I came out of it and you
know what the the really [__] up part
about all of it is like I hosted
NahamCon, I hosted HacktivityCon, I
hosted all my streams with a smile on my
face while on the inside there was so
many things that were happening and
nobody even knew. And when I say Joe was
one of the people that knew about it, uh
Joe came to the house and that he could
see the state that I was in, but when I
was streaming, nobody knew, dude. Nobody
had a clue about what was happening on
the external like you know, from the the
optics of it, nobody knew. I was still
going. I think uh during HacktivityCon,
I think that was in September, a month
before and my old boss, Luke, you guys
both know Luke. He sat me down and was
like, dude, you're not acting like like
yourself. What is going on? And that was
like you know, 7 months into it and I
was like, whoop, since you're asking me,
dude. Uh he's like, you're not acting
like yourself. You're like you know,
short-tempered. That's not who you are.
You're very you're not friendly as you
used to be. You're you're lacking in
decision-making. It's been like
noticeable like because I'm quick to say
this is what we're doing. Like this is
how we're going to do it. And it's like,
what's going on? And I was like, okay,
now I got to tell somebody. So I started
with him, then you know, a couple of
co-workers and then more friends and
more and more people. Yeah, so so you
know, at that point you were starting to
let some of this out and and I know I
think one of the things that is is
tempting as a content creator is to not
let that vulnerability, you know, be
seen, right? Not not you know, put on
that that facade, put on that happy
face, but it really it does you know,
you got to show up as a human each day
to these things be or else it'll eat you
away like you were saying. And I'm
wondering
you know, in the midst of all this of
these stressors, in the midst of a
divorce, in the midst of
you know, some depression, in the midst
of the the the depression of the the
pressure of streaming all the time, how
did this affect you as a hacker? Because
before this,
you were really really, you know, going
really hard on all these programs and
and you had had a
Did we lose him?
There we go.
Um
Before this,
you had been going really hard as a
hacker and hacking a lot of programs,
but if you're streaming, you know, 4
days a week and you're not allowed to
find vulnerabilities live on the stream,
you know, it's mostly just focused on
recon,
how did this how did this affect your
methodology and how did this affect you
as a hacker?
So partially one of the reasons that
actually one of the videos I'm going to
make soon is about I quit. I was going
to say I quit, you know,
streaming and this is why cuz people ask
me like, when are you coming back?
I I'm not going to ever go back. I'm
never going to go back to doing live
recon probably ever again because
when you're doing these like no
vulnerability practices every week, what
you practice it becomes your reality.
When you're not finding vulnerabilities,
it becomes your reality. I'm like, oh,
no.
Especially when it's like recon and like
I'm one of those people that loves like
data, man. Like I love looking at
these data that I find from companies
and like snooping around a company's
infrastructure. It's fun. It's all fun
and games,
but it's not it doesn't translate to
money. So I want to do streams. I'm I'm
not thinking about what I can get back
to making streams and all that stuff,
but it's not going to be the recon stuff
because
I'm not finding vulnerabilities. I'm
doing the same thing over and over and
over again. I've hit this roadblock and
I feel like
I know a lot of people that have learned
from these streams, but I don't want to
keep doing that for the new people. You
can go read what I'm going to maybe do a
couple of them and put them on YouTube
for people to watch, but it's just
you're not finding vulnerabilities and
that becomes your reality of it and
I kind of want to say ever since I
stopped doing it, I've gotten better at
with what I want to do with it as a
hacker, but I also don't want to believe
that because I was doing okay when I was
doing those streams. It's just I got too
comfortable.
Yeah.
I think this is a really common pattern
actually that you see
I mean, I I can think of multiple cases
within the security industry alone where
you've seen this, but people get
they they get known for a niche and they
go, okay, this is my niche.
And that that's them for the next 40
years and they That's in any industry,
right? It's not just Right. Yeah, any
industry. It's not even just security,
right? But like I I can think of
examples everywhere including in
security where this happens and it's
really easy because once you become
known for something,
when somebody goes, hey, do you know
somebody for this thing, your name's
going to come up. And like you have like
instant recognition, you have like
association with being like a top person
within like some certain like pillar or
whatever and like people know your name,
people know that you're like known for
this thing, but it's really hard one,
it's really hard to expand that the
knowledge. So like at a certain point
like you know, the another XKCD about
learning, but it's like you know, the
the learning curve is like He just lives
in XKCD land.
inverse log whatever. You're learning
like a ton like right in the first like
you know, a couple months, first year or
two, whatever and then like by year 20,
you know, it's like half a percent over
the over the last like decade, right?
And so that same thing is true when
you're like focusing focusing focusing
on some niche where you're now like an
expert in this thing, but there's only
so much room for growth for knowledge
within that. Like you can maybe do some
groundbreaking research. Maybe there's
some some new stuff to to expand on, but
a lot of it is like marginal gains
in overall experience and overall
knowledge and instead if you just branch
out into something new, you start that
curve over again. And so the key is what
you're doing, right? Which is like push
yourself. Don't like stick to what's
comfortable. Don't stick to the things
that you know, but like take those
things, push into new fields that you're
not as familiar with, push into new
techniques that you're not as familiar
with so that you can keep yourself on
your toes and keep yourself from falling
into that sort of that comfort zone.
Yeah.
And I feel like with recon it's just
rabbit hole after rabbit hole, dude.
It's like you just find these things you
obsess about and when do you give up?
Like when do you stop, right?
Right. So, just automate the boring
task. If you know how to find something
on that that's automatically, make them
a freaking cron job and have them just
alert you on Discord or alert you on
Slack and
become your, you know, your your your
cash cow and learn other things. It's
just I would be 100% correct though.
Once you become I was becoming like
you know, I was doing stuff with bug
bounties and then I was becoming very
big in recon and I didn't enjoy recon
anymore. It's like everyone that I was
like, "Oh, when are you doing live recon
again? Oh, I love your live recon." Like
that's the only thing that like knew me
for. Where, you know, I did a lot of
stuff in web and I realized with like
bug bounties alone
uh I wasn't making a lot of money from
recon. I was making money from finding
good stuff, but I wasn't making money
from automation, right? I had really
good data a lot of time. Yeah. That
people didn't have. And and that that
brings me back to one of my favorite
quotes that we've had on on this podcast
so far, which was Jason Haddix episode
12. He said, "The point of recon is to
find more apps to hack." You know, and
and I think that's that's just a great
point is like at the end of the day, you
know, you can do these recon finds um
and that sort of thing, but the best
bang you're going to get for your buck
is finding apps and then
drilling deep into those uh those apps
and finding the bugs. And and so Yeah.
in in light of that I kind of there's
two areas that we could go from here. Um
both which are re- related to some
content you've released recently uh and
and principles you've been kind of
talking about in this in this
uh uh content. The first of which is
the switch from the recon to manual.
Um and and we've seen this a lot in in a
lot of the different um
pr- top hackers where there used to be a
lot more of a focus on on recon
um and now there's more of a focus on
manual hunting. As you were making that
switch, you know, in the mi- in the
middle, you know, so did this switch
occur in 2022 when you were coming out
of that scenario or is this something
that happened a little bit later? And
how did that transition occur for you?
The transition didn't really happen
because of like the the content so much.
Like the con- the the the streaming was
a big part of it, right? But
Yeah.
it just happened I needed a change. Like
it wasn't just with hacking. I needed
everything to change. So, I I was
changing my personality to some extent,
my you know, my my appearance. I'd go
into the gym and I'd dieting and things
like that. My hacking style, like
everything that I did. I just wanted to
recreate who I was as a person and even
though my personality isn't my, you
know, hacking, but hacking was a part of
my persona online, that's what it is.
And I really had to figure out what I
wanted to do. And I sat down and went
through all of my reports. Well, how was
I making so much money between the years
of 2015 or 2014 and 2018? Well, A, I
wasn't a manager. I wasn't a senior
manager at HackerOne. That took a lot of
time. But B,
I was just niching down in one single
program. At the time it was Airbnb, a
couple other private programs, but a lot
of times and then I looked at the recon
bugs that I was recon bugs I was finding
wasn't so much of
having the It's nowadays like nuclei
templates and things that were
automated. It was just like I was the
first to find an asset or I was the
first to
um you know, find a functionality or
even like I found an asset that people
just looked over, but it was just, you
know, people knew about it, but no one
found vulnerabilities in them. Those
were my strengths. And with bug bounties
I I really want to tell people like the
biggest things you have to find what
your strengths are. There is no wrong
and right with what you do. If your
strength is to be really good at recon,
then that's your that's your niche. Good
for you. You have to go do that. But if
you're you you want to be a web app
hacker, you want to be good at you know,
breaking apart vulnerabilities in a web
application. If you're good at, you
know, priv esc bugs, there's nothing
wrong with that. That's what you're good
at and some people are [__] at it. You
should be okay with that. And I had, you
know, being a being a top hacker I had a
problem with like well, I don't want to
be this person that's not, you know,
doesn't know these vulnerabilities, but
you know, I don't want to be the elitist
anymore. I don't want to be this like
top hacker. I just want to make money,
make do something I can do, you know,
good with and teach people how to do the
things that I do. So, now I make the
content of things that I enjoy doing.
And if people want to watch it, perfect.
And if they don't, they don't. I no
longer care to justify being a top
hacker anymore. And that's become so
easy now. Yeah, no that that's a I had a
lot of this with mobile hacking as well.
Where like for a long time I associated
and a lot of like my identity was
associated with like being the mobile
hacking guy. And like that's cool. Like
it was awesome for a while, but then I
grew to a point where I was like, "I
want to be doing more than that." And
kind of for like the same reason you
were talking about. Like I didn't want
to fall into this niche where like that
just became like the only thing I did.
And like I don't think I think mobile
hacking is probably big enough where
it's not like
a small niche, you know, where like you
could still probably make a a ton of
money and there's like a lot of research
and stuff you can do there. But I just
want like that I felt like there was
just more that I I could be doing. And
so I started to like push away from
that. But it was such a rough learning
experience because like
I had been used to like, you know,
things coming very easily with like all
the mobile hacking stuff cuz I'd been
doing it for so many years. And then it
was like starting this this different
type of hacking and I was like, "Oh,
wow. This is like
running into a brick wall. Like what
what what do I even do?" Like
just like it really like took me
th- for a loop because it it was such a
learning experience of like adjusting my
hacking flow and how I was approaching
things to be
less targeted towards like what I was
used to and more targeted towards things
I wasn't.
I think the biggest thing that people
like I feel there's a when when you
become when you get into hacking, I
think everybody wants to make it to a
certain point, right? You made it with
mobile hacking. Justin, you've done a
bunch of stuff. I can't even name one
for you, but you have gone through these
phases of doing things, right? But
everybody at some point is going to hit
a blockade of things they do with their
niche. You hit, you know, you hit it
with mobile. You didn't enjoy it or you
learned everything about it, whatever
the reasoning was. I think pivoting as a
whole for us as humans, regardless of
what we do in our life, in our careers,
with hacking, with whatever we do in our
life, pivoting is a huge thing. And a
lot of people don't want to do that.
That includes me. I have a hard time
going out of my comfort zone.
But since I've started pivoting to
different areas, whether it's with my
content, they can, you know,
inspirational content, so technical
content, whether it's doing apps I never
hacked on before, collaborating with new
hackers, putting myself out there, it's
worked out because that's a part of who
you are. That's what that's a part of
it, right? Yeah, no that absolutely. And
I want to double click into that. I
wanted to Go ahead, Joel.
No, you go ahead. No, no, no, you go
ahead cuz I was going to turn this a
whole other way. I was going to say I
want I want to double click into that
for just a second and and talk about a
little bit how you did that from a
technical perspective. So, I know
um you know,
largely recon and web oriented, you
know, in the beginning. And then now
you're kind of pivoting a little bit
over this past year. You mentioned that
you found some vulnerabilities in
desktop apps and other contacts. Um how
did you how did you cut your teeth with
that? How did you get into it?
Well, I was pushed into it, right? So,
two of the instances, one of them was um
the LA event. We can't talk about the
company. That was a big event, right?
And there was a small web portion of it,
but most of it wasn't web. Exactly. And
that forced my hand. I didn't know
anything about that niche of like
hardware hacking at all. That forced my
hand to learn stuff. All right, mobile
hacking as as an example. I didn't know
a whole lot about mobile hacking. I knew
a little bit about like just, you know,
what you can do with a mobile app. You
just, you know, um intercept your
traffic and that's it. But I never did
more than that. That really pushed my
hand to do more. Right? But then uh I
found zero bugs at that event. I showed
up. I refused to do the web stuff. You
know, I I was like, "No. No way I'm
going to cut the web stuff." And then I
realized people were making money from
the web, you know, portion of it, which
is fine. But then
the London event happened.
Mm. And this London event was another
two programs that everybody says looked
at them for years at a time. But there
is a reason why they're doing a live
hacking event. These companies aren't
doing a live hacking event for no
reason. There is more to hack on.
There's definitely more vulnerabilities.
And and me as someone who's been at
almost every live hacking event with
these companies, I've learned there's
always about two to
when these companies come back, right?
Yeah. And it happened again. Those
companies paid about, you know, a
million dollars in bounties. So, those
pushed me and I was like, "Okay, if
everybody's going to look at this London
event that one of the customers,
everyone's going to go after the web
applications and everyone's going to
struggle with finding easy vulns, how do
I change that approach, right? How do I
find these cool bugs within the context
of a desktop app?" Yeah. Those were the
reasons why it pushed me, right? Mm. So,
so what when you're looking at So, in
this scenario you decided to go after
the desktop app. Um and and you you
said, "Okay, I'm going to start looking
into this." I know you ended up teaming
up with Shmoo as well and Alex Chapman,
two two people that have uh you know,
that are pro in in the desktop app
space. Um how much of that was would you
say collaboration based stuff versus you
just kind of sitting down, cutting your
teeth on on desktop apps, reading as
many as much documentation as you can um
versus like combining multiple different
skills from different hackers together,
you bringing your web expertise, them
bringing their desktop expertise and and
creating a a wonderful result?
Funny enough, um the collaboration
didn't happen until the last 4 hours of
that event entirely on day two. So, I
have this vulnerability in this, you
know, desktop app. Uh I couldn't exploit
it. Uh we couldn't figure out what to do
with it. I'm sitting out inside looking
at the door. It's me, couple other
hackers, and God bless his soul, Sam
Curry is sitting right next to me and
he's sitting right next to me. And he's
like You guys know how Sam is. He's very
quiet. He just makes
Yeah. He has these comments he makes
very randomly, right? So, I'm sitting
here I'm like, "Dude, I I know I can RCE
this bug, but I don't know what I'm
doing. Like I have this bug, we don't
know what to do." I think you were maybe
at the table, too. I don't know if you
remember that table.
And then you say something about um
well, why don't you go find someone to
work with? And then Alex is walking in
at this time. Alex and I were just
literally walking. She was sitting right
here next to me and then Sam goes,
"Yeah, Alex is walking. Why don't you go
talk to him? Maybe I bet you he can
exploit it." I go and do that with Shmoo
and we exploit and then I think I put
Sam on that bug for like a 5 or 10% as a
Yeah, of course.
But the the the the point of the story
is like it wasn't like the collaboration
was
planned. I was working on a bunch of
different vulnerabilities. You know, I
you know, I found stuff like um So, the
back to the story for this customer was
there was a lot of CSP limitations. You
couldn't bypass CSP for a lot of times.
And this is within the desktop app,
right?
Yep, but also on the desktop on the web
on the mobile on the core web app of
this company there's a CSP that no one
could bypass. I found a way to bypass
the limitations, which I can talk about
in a little bit. Mhm. But I keep finding
these like HTML injections. Like I could
insert hyperlinks and then I would do
SMB tricks, but I couldn't because, you
know, you can use only one slash. If you
do two slashes, it wouldn't work.
Right. Sure, sure, sure. So, I have all
these I have all these different
vulnerabilities, but I can't exploit a
single thing except I find a bypass
within um the desktop app or in the the
mobile app or even the web app that you
could you do a meta refresh, but instead
of doing two slashes, you can do a
backslash backslash and your Chrome
browser or your browser actually
translates that to slashes. So, the
limitation of doing two slashes with
SMB, you can't do two backslashes with
SMB to do a SMB connection for an RCE.
Right. meta refresh, you can do a
backslash backslash site.com and it
refreshes the entire web page to another
one. In the context of a web app,
doesn't worth isn't worth anything,
right? But in the context of a
desktop app, you can now control that
entire
uh
desktop app that you're working on and
you can do whatever you want with it.
And we need we need to we want to go to
the next phase of it. And just having
that bypass is what made it sweet. I
know three other hackers who had that
vulnerabilities that I couldn't exploit
and no one reported it except one of
them was like, "Hey, I knew this. You
know, can we collaborate?" And we
collaborated with him and then um
Chapman was able to exploit it fully.
Wow, do you That's amazing. So, so to
recap that there, you're finding an HTML
injection inside of the the desktop app.
I don't know, I imagine it's like an
electron app or something like that. And
then and then you're you're using that
HTML injection along with a meta tag to
refresh and use backslashes instead of
slashes. Now you're on your attacker
controlled page inside of the app and
now you you've you've gained control of
the application and then Mr. Chapman
took it from there.
Yeah. And those are the things that I
talk about, right? Like, you know, there
was so many HTML injections that you can
you can have HTML injection on this app,
but nobody for some reason thought about
the the meta refresh. The problem with
the slashes on this particular app was
you can't do URLs because a double slash
translates to a URL or website to them,
so they don't allow it. The backslashes
were saved for us. So, that was a you
know, the example of saying pivoting,
right? It's Okay, this web application I
had a web app bug that got paid really
decently.
Uh it was a cool bug, but this this
particular one was the highest bounty
I've gotten in my life in a given event,
I feel like.
Wow. Right? And it's just pivoting from
I think it was uh
I want to say it was a 40K bounty. Yeah.
They didn't want to give us They didn't
give us credit for it, they gave us high
because we couldn't uh prove full RCE,
but they knew it's exploitable and they
you know, they honored it as a high. But
that's the the the point of pushing
yourself out of your
boundaries, right? It's just going,
"Okay, I know web. I know there's
electron apps, so pretty much like web
applications, but you have more there's
more impact if you can exploit them than
a you know, the traditional XSS. And if
there's CSP in place, you have the
ability of abusing other functionality
that's not, you know, XSS particularly.
So, I I guess I guess in the scenario
the the thing you were talking about
that allowed you to get around the CSP,
that was the meta connect thing. There
wasn't some other thing that allowed you
to get around CSP or Okay.
It was just the meta connect because now
you can point it to another website that
you control and you can put whatever you
want on there. And if you have if you
have XSS and if you have JavaScript in
that context for a electron app, it
doesn't matter.
Mhm. Yeah. Like it doesn't matter where
the JavaScript is being executed from as
long as you need to you know, you're
calling the right functions to download
and execute a file, right? Wow, that's
awesome, man. So, so you used HTML to
redirect the whole page and that's
pretty much
the the only thing I can really think of
that does that is the meta tag. The only
other thing that I can think of is maybe
that like with an iframe. Uh you know,
getting able to iframe another page in
and then execute it, but then that
wouldn't be the top level page. It would
be a sub page. Right.
So, We can do hyperlinks, but when you
do a hyperlink also sometimes it opens
up in actual web browser, right? Cuz
like those are the things that I looked
at. I was like, "Okay, what if I make a
hyperlink?" But no, the easiest route
was the SMB stuff. You just do an SMB to
your box and then that's like automatic
RCE usually, but none of that was
working and I really wanted to I really
This was like one of the first live
hacking events that I was actually
participating in. It's my like second or
third at this point, right? And I really
wanted to find something cool.
Yeah.
And just pushing myself to out of out of
my comfort zone. It's not super out of
your comfort zone. It's just
I don't know anything about electron
apps at this point. I don't know I'm
not, you know, big on JavaScript either.
Like I'm just learning things as I go.
But just doing that, it just opened up a
whole different world for me, dude.
Yeah. No, that that's really makes
sense. So, the last question I had with
regards to that is like and I I don't
know if you can talk about it without
giving away too many details, but I'm
wondering where your your source was for
this. You know, you're sinking you know,
obviously you're you're manipulating the
DOM inside the app. Um but in a desktop
application context, uh you know, how
are you passing data into the app? Is
this something that you you put into the
web application and then it popped up in
the in the desktop app or is this like a
a scheme, a custom URL scheme that they
registered or what?
No, it was actually one of your user
details that showed up on the app a lot.
Um so, you could put your
I I don't know what it was. It may have
been like a signature, username or
whatever. Your name, your something like
that. Like one of the one of the profile
attributes, we'll call it, right?
And it was coming up in this specific
page, but um
it was only in this page that it would
actually pop with the HTML. So, a lot of
times like, you know, I I don't think
this is an issue with XSSs. People are
quick to jump to an alert, right?
Everyone's just like image source alert,
right? My go-to isn't that. My go-to is
just the underline H1 test 123. Yep.
Just because I want I want HTML
injection. I don't care because once you
have HTML injection, it opens up a whole
different world of things you can do.
Whether it's mobile, whether it's web,
whether it's
uh you know, just explo- these uh
binaries for example, desktop apps,
right?
I just care about the HTML injection.
Yeah.
So, seeing that pop was step one. Okay,
now you go to the mobile, you go to the
web app. You go from the web app to the
desktop app. Is it also vulnerable here?
But then that connected me to a bunch of
different things because then I also
realized some of the things that wasn't
rendering on the web app was rendering
in the desktop app as an HTML tag,
right? Wow. Okay. So, that opens up a
lot more. It's same thing with mobile.
You you put something So many of the
bugs that I found this year were
exclusively only popping up on this
mobile application and not on the web uh
web version of it.
Wow. Yeah, so I was going to ask like
sort of how this speaks to sort of your
your overall hacking methodology. Um and
and I think this is maybe a good time to
start to like talk about sort of like
how you approach targets. I'm sure
you've talked a a bunch about this on
your on your streams and in your videos
and stuff.
Yeah, yeah, never. Yeah, talk about
hacking. I don't think you've ever done
that.
But uh but like it sounds like a lot of
it sort of comes from very like simple
straightforward testing, right?
Like underline H1 AST123 like Yep. look
just spray and pray. And like how how
much further than just like that payload
are you are you testing before like
obviously when you see something that's
like HTML injection, you're going to
follow up on that, but
how much are you modifying your
payloads? Like how how much will you
test one field? Like do you spend all
day on one page or what how fast are you
switching between stuff? Can you walk me
through that a little bit?
Yeah, so a lot of times like I think
it's pattern recognition. I think like
99% of bug bounties is I don't care what
you say is pattern recognition. You you
identify a pattern of mistakes the
particular company and you just exploit
the [__] out of it. That's what it is.
That's the reality of it, right?
So, if I know a company is, you know, um
good I I know that XSS is a big part of
like the issues, then I'm probably
spending more time
fuzzing specific fields, but it's I
don't change the
the input that I put in that often. It's
It's one thing that I put. It's like a
couple of you know, different quotes,
different encrypting, different um
uh HTML entities or something like that
for example. It's just a bunch of
different characters that I put in as a
polyglot for example and I put it in
there and I analyze or over analyze the
[__] out of it until I move on to the
next field. But
a lot of times
I'm trying to explain how to say this.
So, it's the same payload until it fires
up, right? Then what you do next is
different based on the target, based on
your end goal, what you're going to do
with it. Like you want to you want to do
an XSS or maybe you can push it to the
PDF for example or maybe you can push it
into some server side stuff and become
the blind XSS. Then that objective
changes, right? But a lot of times it's
the same payload that I put in just to
see how the the application is going to
react to my user input.
That that that's really interesting
because
there's there's like this concept of a
polyglot like a benign polyglot payload,
right? Cuz if you look up XSS polyglot,
you'll kind of see, you know, all sorts
of JavaScript URLs and you know, weird
comments and text to click.
Different ways to write script, yeah.
Exactly. And Those aren't used. Yeah,
that's not what I use though. I'm saying
just just uh
I make my own. It's like my own homemade
few tags, few characters, things that I
know is going to break out of an input
field, it's going to break out of a
script tag, it's going to break out of a
text area, it's going to break out of X,
Y, and Z. And then looking at the DOM, I
spend a lot of time chasing those. The
reason why I do like test1234 is because
I chase that taste test 123 within the
domain and see where it all shows up,
right?
That's one of the things that if you
just put like a if you just put test
test on it isn't anything to chase, but
if you do test 1234 something very
unique to you, then it's it's easier to
follow up.
Yeah, and that that's great and it
really makes sense on on why you would
do the you know, benign payloads, but
also have the polyglot. So it is a
really good exercise for the listener,
you know, it to go look at what the
polyglot payloads that are out there are
doing in particular and why they have to
be as complex as they are and then
simplify them down to to make a a
polyglot that works only in the HTML
injection context that doesn't have the
goal of cross-site scripting because the
first step to getting cross-site
scripting is getting HTML injection in
you know, x x amount of the scenarios.
Obviously, you got to account for the
location based sinks or whatever, but um
I think that's a really a really great
piece and and it you know, it
not using a polyglot and just using
double quote h1, you're going to miss
stuff, you know, and if if you use the
polyglot, you're going to miss stuff. So
you got to find that nice sweet sweet
spot where you're not getting too
verbose and you're not being too simple
either.
But there's also two things to that. One
is if you put like, you know, very
obvious HTML tags, it sometimes it gets
filtered. So the objective isn't just to
get HTML injection in there, it's also
to break out of whatever current context
you're in because there's going to be
times where I put my payload in it it
breaks out, but the filtering takes out
some of the HTML actually helps me break
out of it because it's taking things out
and putting it together or
or whatever.
it. It's replacing converting it, right?
So that's a big part of it, but I also
want to you know, you know, I want to
really kind of like caution people of
this also like when you put something
like a script or if you put event
handlers in there, it might just strip
out the entire string you gave it by
default and say, "Oh, I see I see bad.
I'm going to take it all out, right?" So
that's why the the the the the reason
why I do it is the particular order
particular way just to see can I break
out of this before I even think about
exploitation. Can I break out of this
thing that hints to me like, "Hey, this
is a vulnerability here." and look at
it. I always I always think And this
kind of goes back to what I was
Well, I was going to say that this kind
of like the the whole like dictionary
encyclopedia thing I was talking about.
And you mentioned rabbit holes as well.
Like I feel like all these things sort
of play together where it's so easy to
like fall down an infinite rabbit hole
of just like
you could test every possible
every payload, everything on one field
and you can do that for every single
field. Uh but you have to draw the line
somewhere.
Um do you
have a like a spot where you draw that
line? Like where do you where you decide
like, "Okay, I think this is like enough
testing on
on this setting spin or whatever?" Uh I
feel like by the dictionary by the um
the definition of dictionary, I may be
considered as insane.
Because a lot of times I keep repeating
the same thing that's not like doing
anything for me.
And then like suddenly it works because,
you know, like it didn't work 3 months
ago and now it works suddenly because
they made a change in the code, right?
So I feel by definition I may be a
little crazy, but I don't have a you
know, it's not like I'm sitting here
going, "Oh, I spent like 4 days on this
thing." because I feel like one there's
there's your instincts, right? It says,
"I know there is something here, right?"
Like you you you have this instinct that
like
it comes after years of experience that
you go, "I can feel there's something
here." and then you maybe you don't
exploit it and somebody else does,
right? And you go, "Fuck, I could have
done that or I should have done that I
should should have done this for it." So
I for that reason I spend a lot of time.
It goes back to my my personality being
like addicted to wanting to do these
specific way. But then that's why I get
burnt out sometimes just because I'm
spending spending, you know, countless
days on the same thing over and over and
over again and then
suddenly I have this my ADHD kicks in so
I'm like, "Okay, let's jump around a
little bit." So no, if there is if there
is a particular like portal or settings
page or something that looks really
fishy, I'm going to throw a bunch of
things at it. So my thing goes I'm going
to try everything I know. Everything I
know in the in my in the books in my
tricks in my sleeve everything I try.
Then I I share it with my inner circle,
right? If I'm not collaborating with
them a lot of times and if I'm doing
something solo, then I go, "Yo, I found
this thing." I think Justin has gotten a
bunch of like random [__] you even you
Joel have to come like random stuff that
over time and I'm like,
"Dude, I smell a vuln here. Like can you
like it look at it?" And then they they
throw me ideas, right? Like they give
you things that you didn't think about
or it maybe like an idea and then I do
that. Then it's when I go, "Okay, I'm
going to open source this." and I go on
Twitter I go, "I have this thing." I
think you've seen like a bunch of times
I tweet these things. I go, "I'm
fighting this thing. These are the
things I have tried. Give me your best
shot." and then people give me ideas and
then I just give up at some point. Yeah.
But I have to go through that list to
make sure I've covered it because a lot
of times
I've learned with the live hacking
events I look at it and I go, "Well, son
of a [__] I could have I should have
tested that." Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. I will say nowadays it's great
because during the show and tell I'd say
like
earlier on in the live hacking cycle, I
would see the show and tells and I'd be
like, "Oh, I should have tested that
thing." but like I just didn't and like
that's why I missed it. Now it's like I
should have tested that thing and
there's no way in hell I would have
tested what they just tested to get that
bug. So good on them.
But also the other thing is like but for
me also the other thing about it is that
sometimes I sit and I go, "Well, good
for them because at least somebody
figured it out or this bug would have
gone to waste." So I like I sit there
and I go, "Damn, I should have tried
that." but then at least somebody
figured it out, right?
Yeah, yeah, exactly. Exactly. For sure.
So so from there I I kind of want to
continue going down this path of hacking
methodology and then we'll we'll bounce
around a little bit into some technical
stuff into some uh I guess bug bounty
related statistics, but um
So it it basically what you what you
just said, it sounds like you're a
little bit more of a thorough hacker. We
we one of the questions we ask a lot on
the pod is like, "How soon do you jump
around before you
you know, if you haven't found a bug,
how long do you give a program?" Um and
so it sounds like if you're throwing
your whole hat of tricks at it, you
know, it it might take a little while.
Is that accurate or
It honestly depends. Um it all it all
depends on my workload to be honest. Ah.
Like it depends on what I got going on
that week. So there's times when you
know, when like a live hacking event,
there is no there's no giving up because
live hacking event coming up there's a
lot of there's a lot for grabs and then
it's like a personal vendetta that like
I need to make this work. I want to have
a bug. I want to continue this event.
Right? That's a different story, but
with like
with the programs that I hack on I've
become very selective. I just I select
programs that I know A it's going to pay
me enough.
It's going to be worth the you know, the
the 3 days of not finding vulns or 3
weeks of not finding vulns on going down
this rabbit
Damn it.
Sorry.
All good.
I like that it has its own like effect
for it. It's like when my camera dies,
it's not nearly that cool.
It just dies. I still have not figured
out how to get this out of idle for
every 30 minutes it does this.
That's that's hilarious. Yeah, for those
of you listening his camera's going off
you know, into rainbow mode every once
in a while.
Um
yeah. But yeah, it it all depends. Like
you know, it depends on depends on my
workload, but with live hacking events
there's no stopping and then there are
times where a a company comes up that I
really want to hack on, right? So I'll
give you an example of um
I got asked to do a presentation for
this company
um they have a web app, mobile app,
desktop app and I had a month and a half
to prepare for it, but naturally I was
traveling live hacking events live
whatever. I have a week. That whole week
I did not stop until I found the vuln
the night before the presentation.
There's no stopping until that goal
happens. I don't have a I wish I had a
good way of saying this is where I draw
the line. It all comes down to my
workload. If I know that tomorrow I have
to make content the next I have to do x
y and z and then I have to travel to
somewhere else, I'm probably going to
give up within the you know, my when my
first 3 days are up. Like I spent 2 3
days on this app, nothing happens, time
to move on, time to cut my losses. But
if it's an if it's a company that I
hacked on in the past I've had good
results with, then I push that more and
more because I know I've gotten a bounty
from this company before. I know the
patterns of mistake. I'm willing to
spend more time because I know the ROI
is there. Yeah. Yeah, that that that
makes a lot of sense, you know, when
you've established an a relationship
with a company and even 3 days is is
pretty long for
some of the researchers that we've
talked to where
uh what it I always think Douglas is
hilarious. Douglas is like, "If I don't
find a bug in like 3 hours, then I
normally just move on." And I'm like,
"What the what the heck are you like
what are you doing, man?" I mean that's
3 days.
That's the thing though that that that
depends on the 3 days cuz the 3 days
isn't like I'm doing 8-hour days.
Right. It's the first day I'm doing you
know, the first four you know, the way I
look at it is like the first 4 hours is
really like, "What the [__] am I doing?"
Exactly. Yeah.
What is this app? What am I supposed to
do? What are the patterns of mistakes?
I'm just plugging things in and just
observing and like taking in everything
the application does. The second day is
like
"Okay, now you really Now you're getting
I'm getting pissed off, right?" And then
I'm going to go a little bit harder to
find I'm going to like extend my attack
surface as we call it, right? Then the
third day is like, "Okay, dude, like
either I [__] find something today or
I just don't I I give up. I'm [__]
done." I feel like you guys seen this a
lot of in your groups, right? He's
pounding the table, too. It's
it's so funny. Um yeah, dude, 100% and I
think it's funny you mentioned 4 hours
cuz that's kind of that's exactly the
same length of time that I always allot
for for that first little bit is like,
"All right, the first 4 hours or so I'm
just trying to figure out what this app
does, how how to use it." You know,
reading the documentation, stepping
through it. You know, I have no
expectations of finding bugs within the
first 4 hours of hacking. And then after
after that, you know, like you said, the
stages continue to grow where it's like
if I haven't found anything by day 3,
I'm like, you know, really having a
vendetta against this app. Um
so that's that's hilarious that we're
we're both sort of on that same front.
So that I looked it up online. It's the
there's four stages of anger. It's
annoyed, frustrated, hostile, and
enraged. I don't get to enraged unless
it's required. I just looked it up.
I stop at the third level. So and I
think it kind of describe it pretty well
at this point. So Uh yeah. So so I
actually I I want I want to go back and
talk about that because you said, you
know, sometimes you're working for 4
hours. Um I struggle especially with
having another thing, right? Having the
podcast to to cuz I need contiguous
time. I need, you know, long periods of
time where I can stay focused and hack.
I can't hack for an hour then go do
something then come back hack for an
hour then go do something come back hack
for an hour. Um do you have that same
experience and how do you balance
hacking with content creation? Like do
you lot certain days of the week or do
you do you, you know, just hack after a
certain time or how does that work?
Yeah. So a day day in life of the homie.
A day in life of the Yeah. So usually I,
you know, like I wake up. I I do my the
the thing So funny enough, I don't
consider hacking something that takes a
lot of brain power because I feel like
once you sit down your computer, you're
on autopilot, right? Like you know what
to do. You know, you know, you it's your
the comfort thing for me. I get
comfortable with hacking, right?
Yeah. So
morning is like all the calls, all the
meetings, you know, I working with the
with the stuff that I'm building,
working on content, you know, emailing,
community [__] whatever you want to
call it, right? That's what I do in the
mornings. So it's my first, you know, 8
to noon, maybe 8 to 2 sometimes. Then at
about 2:00 is when I want to switch. So
I go to the gym usually for about an
hour then I come home, maybe take an
hour off, maybe, you know, I go to like
a hot my hot tub or I shower
Yeah, hot tub. Let's go. hot tub
I feel like I'm the only hacker without
a hot tub. Well, why don't you why don't
you come over and we'll redo this
episode at one point from my hot tub.
This guy wants to I would love that. All
right.
I love that.
a hot tub.
But I I have a disconnect of a of a
shift in my, you know, in my brain. I
shift it over to something else. So then
I'm doing a pen test, I'm bug bounty
hunting, or
whatever. That's the case for like my
regular days. That doesn't include life
hacking events, but a lot of times
you'll see me do like get all my
meetings out of the way.
2:00, 3:00 go to the gym, come back and
switch over to hacking because it's just
easier and then I can, you know, I can
have stuff happening or you know, I'll
make food and I you know, do something
and then go back and forth for like, you
know, 4 to 6 hours a day.
But there's also times when you're
getting success that makes it harder
though, right? Like there was there's
when I hit those huge bug bug bounty
month that I was doing, there was no
boundaries at all. It was 8:00 I was
waking up. I was doing bug bounty things
like for 2 hours then doing calls,
meetings, going to the gym, coming back,
doing it and then just, you know, I'm
just going to go stir crazy cuz I'm so
hyped over it. Those are the edge cases,
you know, life hacking events are edge
case for it. But typically I try to have
that shift where I do my day work, just
get all the boring tasks out of the way.
Everyone's awake, you know, Adam I work
with is in London, so I to wake up early
to work with him sometimes.
Right. People that want to, you know,
people want to people have 9 to 5s that
want to meet with you, they're not going
to meet with you in, you know, they want
to meet with you in the morning. So
prioritize those and then I do that. You
have to have that mentality shift. And I
also surprisingly don't do my hack out
of this room. This is purely meeting,
content, Really? Interesting. I like to
I sit crisscross applesauce, headphones
in on the couch.
Uh I don't care whether something's on
the TV or not, but no, I have to sit on
the couch comfortably with my feet like
crisscross and just sitting there in my
cat position where I'm comfortable and
just hacking from the couch.
I agree. I was I was going to say that I
had a couple things I was going to say,
but like that's true for me too. Like I
find it even though I have like this
really nice setup, it's very difficult
for me to like feel comfortable hacking
when I'm like in such a structured
environment. I feel like a lot of the
time the best hacking that I do is when
I'm just like sort of on the fly like ad
hoc. I'm just sitting next to somebody
or I'm just like chilling and I've just
like got my laptop pulled out or
whatever and I I'm just like fiddling
with stuff. Um yeah, that that That's
awesome. The other thing I was going to
say
um was how do you uh how do you manage
like the
uh the energy aspect of it because you
mentioned like you start hacking like
3:00 after like a day of like meetings
and whatever and stuff. For me I can be
totally drained by 3:00 and like that's
very difficult to to keep up the energy
level and sort of like the mental
stamina to to keep pushing after sort of
like that hump in the day. Yeah. Um do
you have like hacks that you use
personally to get over that or or how do
you how do you do that?
depends on the day, right? Like you are
going from a your daytime job where you
have I'm sure you have somebody you
report to and people that report to you.
You have responsibilities.
That the the structure of a corporate
job is different than when you work for
yourself, I feel like. Because I don't
have except for the couple people that I
work with me on my team,
I don't have to manage them, right? They
they have their projects. I do my part,
they do their part. We're good, right? I
don't have that mental block of like,
oh, I got to meet with my boss and
explain the things that I've done this
week because I'm responsible for them.
No, I it's me, you know, it's me and me.
Oh, let me call my boss. Can I get today
off? Yep, you're off today, right?
That's the the the truth of it, right?
When I make fun of I do this with my
friends. I can you My boss is really on
my ass right now. But my buddies are
we're we're hanging out like, hey, can
you message your can you tell us if you
can do this on Friday? I I go, hey, can
you get today off? Oh, wait, I have
Friday off now. Okay, cool.
Dude,
But that's the that's a good thing about
working for yourself, right? I said but
It is. It doesn't mean It doesn't mean
that I don't have the days where like I
have, you know, back-to-back meetings
and then I have a really [__] hard
day and I don't want to hack. I have
those days and I go, eh,
whatever. I'm not going to hack today.
Like it happens. And that's yeah. That
that's the nice part about
events are the not included in that.
Yeah, no, no, no. Those those are
different animal. That's the nice part
about being self-employed and
particularly full-time bug bounty is I
feel like if you're good enough at bug
bounty, you can do that, right? Because
you're making enough money to say like,
hey, I actually really don't feel like
hacking today. And that was one of the
mistakes I made earlier on in my in my
full-time bug bounty career was like I
was like getting on my own ass every
single day if I wasn't out there, you
know, uh
hacking stuff and then Mariah tells me
one day she's like, Justin, you don't
need to you know, if you don't feel like
hacking today, just take the day off,
you know, and and come back at it when
you love it and when you're inspired by
it and when you're, you know, hyped for
it and you're going to get way better
results. Um which I think is really true
and I'm glad uh you know, you've learned
that lesson and uh it seems like
Absolutely, man. from the way that
you've described it, you have uh
you've managed the stress aspect of
having the content and the hacking
together really well, which is something
I'm still I'm still trying to uh to
balance on myself.
gentle with yourself, man. Like only you
know what internally you're going
through. I'm sure I'm sure with like
Mariah knows a lot of it, but you know
what's going on inside, right? There are
days when I just even with life hacking
events sometimes I go, you know, what?
[__] it. Worst is I don't find anything.
Yeah.
It's not an easy shift. So when I went
from a daytime job to working for
myself, it was really hard because
how do you
What is the How do you measure that,
right? How do you measure success with
not working a 9 to 5? You can't, right?
It's really hard because, you know, you
go, oh, if I don't make money, who do I
blame? Or if I make more
Right, it's just you have you're the
only one that responsi- is responsible.
So you also have to have that
relationship with yourself to be able to
say, you know, what? Today was a rough
day and I just want to hang out and like
watch movies or I just want to play
video games or whatever that is. Yeah.
My thing is a lot of times I try not So
when I'm doing like these I go through
these sprints, right? I try to do like I
go, I'm going to do the I'm going to go
grind out bug bounties for a while and
then I'm going to be done for it. During
those times I tell myself like by 8:00,
9:00 try and just like disconnect and go
play some video games or watch a movie,
watch a TV show or something. So but
like about like 8:30, 9:00 if my friends
text me like, hey, Call of Duty tonight,
you know, [__] it. Yeah, I'm going to
get on and play games with them. 100%.
to be okay with having those because if
you're not doing that, um
then that's how burnouts happen.
The reality of it is it's going to
happen. What about weekends? Do you work
on weekends or do you do you mostly take
weekends off? Um I don't have the
concept of working. I've I've tried to
get rid of the concept of 9 to 5 and
weekday week weekends. If I feel like
Saturdays are the day I kind of do
stuff. It's like I catch up on some
stuff. Sundays, no, I don't work because
I I tell myself you need one day for
yourself. And it's not to not work. I
still work on Sundays. I make my
thumbnails and like I prep videos on
Sundays, but it's not I'm not I don't
have a set schedule. Sundays is laundry
day
and maybe some bug bounty stuff if I
feel like it like if if I have, you
know, if I have the time, but I want to
have a day where I don't have a
schedule. Monday through Friday I have a
schedule of like I got to do calls and
all these things and then Saturday is
like it's a mix of both, but I'm not
putting the pressure on myself to say I
have to work this Saturday. But if I go,
ah, I kind of want to do this right now,
it's work that I'm going to jump on and
do it. Mm. So you want to have, you
know, on my Sundays it's a no play, but
Saturday is like I'm going to work I
have I play chess on Saturdays every
Saturday I go and play this guy at a at
a coffee shop. I met him randomly like 2
months ago and now every Saturday I go
play with him, but I make that time. I
go, okay, if you're working, at least
take the time to go play chess with Roy,
hang out with him and then go back to
whatever you were doing. Nice. Shout out
to Roy. He'll never watch this, but
shout out to that.
Shout out to Roy. Yeah. That's awesome,
dude. Well, okay, so this isn't a great
transition, but I did want to talk a
little bit about cuz you mentioned this
at the beginning. Okay. Um you mentioned
that you saw like huge growth uh during
one quarter um uh of of your of your
journey. And I guess this kind of does
play play a little bit with like the
motivation and burnout aspects and
stuff. Uh I'm looking at this this photo
that you put in the doc here. And uh
This is this is bug bounty stats right
now you're looking at, Rachel. Oh yeah,
bug bounty stats. Yes, bug bounty stats.
I mean this spike in Q3 is bananas,
right? It's like
twice your best quarter other like maybe
even more than twice your best quarter
otherwise. Yeah. Can you tell me a
little bit about sort of what what
happened there? Was there anything in
particular that changed that sort of
created that? Was it Is it sustainable
to keep at that pace? Like tell me a
little bit about what what happened in
Q3. Um a lot of things happened. So, in
um
November of 2022
is when I left my job and I was jobless
and it was more of a okay, well, time to
find I was thrown into like the the
dream that I had like eventually working
for myself. Not on my terms, but I was
pushed to finally have to do this,
right? So, naturally the first quarter
I'm just going insane. What am I going
to do? You know, I want to What am I
going to work on? How am I going to make
money? What am I going to do to like
enjoy what I do? All that stuff.
Q2 is
So, Q1 is just like planning, planning.
These are my goals. I'm very much like
goal-oriented. Like I have to write down
my goals and how am I going to achieve
them.
I wish I had this. Hold on, let me show
it to you.
I have this journal.
If anyone wants to actually, you know,
follow along and do this also, I really
recommend it.
Um it's called the Best Self Journal and
it allows you to set up three goals.
I'm not going to share those with you,
but this is what a day-to-day looks
like. It gives you this page.
Right here it says today's goal, what
you're grateful for, today's three
targets, your to-do list, and what would
make today great.
It is insanely cool and let me see if I
have an empty page of it. I'll have to
actually show you how you can set up
your goals. Um
So, it lets you set up goals and it says
like how do you, you know, what is this
goal? What are the the milestones for it
and that's how you plan it. So, every
week you plan it and you put your goals
right here and you go after it. I'm very
much so I want to do this. So, in Q2 it
was just more of a get it together for
bug bounties. Like you know, if you
wanted to do
if you want to make decent amount of
money, bug bounties is probably the
easiest way to do it where you can make
enough money to also not worry about
your bills, but you while you launch
your company and do things.
Q3 was when that came to reality because
I started hacking more on this bug
bounty program. They did a live hacking
event with HackerOne and I also started
collaborating with who I didn't
collaborate with in the past. Like more
seriously collaborate. And then finally
finding the balance in Q3 between
content, hacking, and what what do what
I want to do? Like what do I want to do
that I'm going to at least be happy. So,
you know, in the beginning of the year I
was happy. I told myself if I make 80k
this year, I'll be happy.
Yeah.
But it's a scary thing because I've
never done bug bounties like this,
right? Bug bounties was never my source
of income. It was always like I knew it
was doable, but I was just like okay, if
I No, sorry, but it's not fair to say
80k. 80k was what I could do to be
comfortable living. So, if I make 80k, I
could comfortably live and pay my bills
and not be, you know, not be stressed.
But that's what happened in Q3, a lot of
it. It was more of a figuring out the
balance, figuring out the day-to-day
that I told you like oh my god, this is
working. You know, working on content in
the morning, gym, and then hacking is
working. Collaborating with people like
Ziad, Shawn, and other people really
helped. So, it's just figuring that out
and just saying okay, I'm going to keep
doing this until the wheels fall off.
Yeah. Okay. So, then what when I look at
the graph, if I could just follow up on
that,
I then see Q4. Now, Q4 was second best
quarter of the year. But what what
did did you sort of get more relaxed?
Like holidays and stuff? Like what was
did, you know, what what was the
difference because it sounds like you
kind of had figured it figured it out in
Q3. So, I would expect Q4 to be like the
same or better, but I understand things
happen. Well, no, with Q3, so I wasn't,
you know, with with this
specific program, we'll call it um
with this program, I I was hacking on it
before and I wasn't taking it seriously.
Just like okay, I'm going to make some
money and
you know, it's great they give me some
money here and there, cool. I'm making,
you know, a bounty
every week, cool. But then H1702
happened and a lot of people think like
at H1702 I was hacking on like some, you
know,
specific like app that no one had access
to.
Half of it is correct. I found something
that no one had access to, but also I
realized like
there's so much of this specific company
you can hack on that you can't even wrap
your head around it. It's such a
ginormous company, right?
So, Q3 is that realization and then
going from the H1702 event to Q4 is when
I was like okay, time to double down on
this company. There's people are making
a ton of money. Why can't I do the same
thing? And Vegas was an example of it.
When I came out of Vegas, it was just I
wrote that high of Vegas for 3 months,
dude.
Yeah.
That's awesome. I mean, I know that you
like you once you like, you know, you
hit those goals, you're like you know
what?
I'm going on a trip. I'm going to go on
my birthday. Like I was thinking and I
was like hell yeah, dude. So, it's so
well deserved. And I think you still
actually like got a bunch more bounties
after that too, right? Yeah. Absolutely,
yeah, but I just want to I can mention
like it's it's a lot of figuring things
out. Like figuring out what worked,
figuring out what schedule worked for
me, figuring out like holy [__] I have
this program that's paying a lot of
money.
You can see the build up. Q1 they paid
me a little bit of bounty. Q3 is when I
was like holy crap, like this is the
reality of it. I can make this money.
You know, if I can make, you know, 30,
40k a month from this bug bounty
program, that's a lot of money. Yeah.
Yeah. 100% and I think it shows as well.
The it shows as well, you know, it took
you a a year to crack that code. You
know, you started in November 2022 and
then, you know, Q3 of of 2023 is when
this really, you know, started
manifesting. And I'm looking at this
chart as well. This is the same chart
that we talk about a lot. This is the
submissions by severity or or
submissions, you know, in a quarter
period
from the HackerOne performance tab. And
I'm seeing almost all of these are
highs. There's there's almost no mediums
and no lows. And there's quite a few
criticals, but the overall the vast
majority of these are highs.
And I imagine that's because you sort of
cracked the code on how to get a bug,
you know, qualified as a high on
and and that would really allow you to
increase your earnings a lot because
every little mistake they make, now you
figured out a way to work that into a
high and you can repeat that success
over and over again. Is that is that
accurate?
It is, but it's also how they perceive a
vulnerability. Like what they why they
what they consider as a high. But also a
lot of times it's just connecting
things. Like saying okay, maybe like
they call this a medium, but then you
extend it to another application and you
can elevate that to a high, right? I'm
trying to like talk about these
vulnerabilities vaguely as I can.
But yeah, it's a it's a lot of times
just knowing
if you prove one case to them as a high,
then everything else is considered as a
high to them. It's the same root cause
for them. But some of these bugs were
also
um like
things that I've never explored in the
past. Like there were there were a
couple of things that I never thought I
could find in this company.
It's just going down a list of these
vuln types and being able to go I did
this one, I did this one, I did this
one, I did this one.
And going through it.
Yeah, and and I'm looking at the other
the other, you know, breakdown here,
submissions by weaknesses. And we're
seeing a lot of XSS, seeing a lot of
access control, and a lot of IDOR as
well.
Would you say that those are like, you
know, the bread and butter for you as
far as vulnerabilities goes? And then I
know XSS There's there's a big category
there. Yeah, yeah, but there's also the
no weakness type because a lot of those
the no weakness ones are a chain of like
different vulnerabilities.
And with the XSS ones, so like I'll give
an example for the XSS ones,
if you
So,
this is a mistake on my end. For
example, if I
RCE'd a desktop app
because of the
with the cross-site scripting, the root
cause is cross-site scripting.
Right? So, there's a couple of those
that are, you know, there's I want to
say there's like 10 of those that are
like that. The root cause is cross-site
scripting. The reality of it is
cross-site scripting, but it's just how
you exploit it and how you, you know,
show impact to get more money.
Some of them are like mobile related
that I owned the mobile app a couple of
times, but again the root cause is
cross-site scripting again. So, there's
a lot of those things. It's just that
comes to going to like finding out
different contexts of vulnerabilities
and how they're working in different
areas of the, you know, this company,
mobile apps, web apps, desktop apps, and
stuff like that.
Okay. This is this is a little on the
spot.
How many dupes did you get this year? Do
you know?
Um actually, can I check for that? Let
me see.
Yeah. Go go go ahead and check on that.
And and I think I think it's
I think it's interesting that you
highlighted that piece about XSS because
it is so so
like you're able to do so much with it.
You can you can escalate it in a web
context. You can try to pivot it to a to
a an a mobile app or to a desktop app.
And then even, you know, just within the
web context you have a lot of ways that
you can exploit with getting access to
session information,
cookie bombing. Like there's there's
just very few other vuln types that you
can chain as well as an XSS to achieve
some crazy stuff.
So, with the duplicates, it's loading.
You have to think about a bunch of them
are duplicates of my own like my own
bugs also.
Right. Right. Right. That's tricky.
Yeah.
So, it's two pages worth. I'm assuming
it's 25 a page or one or two pages for
25. It's about less than 50.
No, wait, there's more. Actually,
there's there's a third page. Hold on,
there's three pages. So, about
50 to 75. Nice. But there is a vast
there's a large number of them that's
like oh, you know, it's different
functionalities, but, you know, it's the
root cause is the same. But yeah, about
75 and I don't submission-wise, I wish I
had the number for how many I submitted,
but I think I submitted a lot this year.
Yeah, I think you can find that number
some number somewhere. And I think it
would be interesting to see the dupes
dupes to
valid ratio.
my triage and valid Yeah, let me see
what my my triage and resolves are.
Yeah, or you can say one of the easiest
ways to do it is to do bounty awarded
and then select, you know, that that
date range within within the filtering
settings there. Um 146 is my number of
closed as resolved and triage right now
for 1123 to 1124. Wow, dude. So so
you're reporting you're reporting like
200 over probably over 200 bugs in in in
2023.
Oh, 61 duplicates. There we go. The the
number for customers is going to 61
duplicates and the 140 something that
was my
valid triage then.
Yeah, so right about 200 and
Wow. about 25 little over 25%.
Yeah.
Yeah. Wow. That's That's pretty solid.
That's amazing. So so you know, jumping
off off the back of that XSS piece, one
of the the technical, you know, sections
that we wanted to talk about while
you're on here is the blind XSS.
And I think that this is a category that
not a lot of people specialize in. So
it's cool to have you come on the show
and say like, yeah, blind XSS is kind of
my thing.
So can you talk a little bit about A
does a vulnerability class perhaps just
provide an introduction to it and then
we'll kind of dive into what kind of
payloads you're using, what kind of
platform, you know, you're using for
that and custom mods to XSS payloads.
So first of all, I don't consider myself
to say blind XSS is my thing. I just
happen to be very like
blessed with it this year. Sure. Sure.
Sure. Big portion of this also goes to I
got to give a big shout out to Z Shano
for this specifically because he is also
pushed me a lot or pushed my buttons
also a lot to find more more blind cross
site scripting and just like bouncing
ideas with me and you know, just you
know, going to him and venting to him
sometimes. It's the same thing with Ziad
also. I just got to give them two two a
shout outs
before I start. But blind XSS just the
same as your regular stored XSS I want
to say. A lot of times it's stored more
than reflected. But the difference is
instead of it happening on the front end
that you see, it happens on the back end
where the companies team sees it. So
think about you know, if HackerOne had a
back portal for example where you can
see your reports, you have a cross site
scripting payload that doesn't, you
know, fire in the report section but it
fires in HackerOne's back end. Funny
enough, if you look up, I actually had
that happen to HackerOne once No way. I
was working there. Oh my god. That's
amazing.
fired off in our internal network at
HackerOne. But yeah, it's just a lot of
it is you just learn that these
companies make mistakes. They the
mistakes don't happen in the front end a
lot of times. It happens in the back end
because they go, well, no one's going to
ever see this and we don't have to worry
about it. And guess what? It does happen
a lot more than you can expect.
And and so I I that exact rationale was
what I wanted to talk to you about. How
do you identify
what pieces of information are going to
end up in an admin panel somewhere?
You know, where where do you get those
ideas?
I think it's very I want to say it's I
don't want to say it's common sense but
it's just very like it's the thing that
you think a company wants to collect on
you, right?
Yeah. So when you register, what matters
to that you that's your name, your email
address, your address, your credit card
information in some cases,
anything that could identify you as a
duplicate account for example like they
could say these are the same user. So
that could be your browser information
for example and things like that. And
then things that could also trace as you
like when you have different websites
and things like that, right? It's how do
they identify you as a user and you as a
browser or you know, not the user itself
but like the the
I don't know like the browser for
example or the
the device. We'll say the device for
example. So those are the things that I
look at, right?
Those are the things that I always
assume companies are collecting on you.
But then also it goes the information
that you put in to the company. So
let's talk about
let's say like Spotify for example. You
guys post your podcast on there, the
description, the the guest, the name of
the, you know, you guys and those are
also things that they collect.
But they could, you know, people would
probably find those XSS early on in the
days of those programs but they don't
think about like, oh, I wonder if this
fires here, is it going to also fire in
the back end? And if it does, how do I
get them to fire on that back end,
right? Those are the things that you
have to figure out. You have to assume
how do I go from A to B? Your A is I
have XSS on the core app. How do I get
to fire on the back end? How do I get
this engineer, the support person
without social engineering, naturally go
click on it? Okay, so that's that's
where I was going next with that was
like, okay, so we've got infor
information, we put it in, we're using a
blind XSS payload that we can get a call
back from. Yeah. How do we how are we
going to be the one user that the
support agent clicks on or the, you
know, back end analytics admin clicks
on?
I'm not thinking of I don't I don't know
how to say this. I don't want to
me. I know. I know what you're going to
say here. I know what you're going to
say here.
What do you Joe, what do you think I'm
going to say? I want to see what you you
think. Oh, we can cut this out if we
need to.
No, go for it. Go for it. You just you
open a support chat and you say, hey,
I'm having an issue with this thing and
you send it to them and they they click
it. That that is that is that is also
that's a very good approach but no, the
I I don't want to promote committing
fraud. I want to start with that. Yeah.
But fraud detection is a big PART OF
TECHNOLOGY.
HOW DO YOU GET What's the easiest way to
get banned on a platform?
Right? What's the easiest way? What is
the easiest way for them to be like,
holy crap, who is this guy? What do we
do? What do we do to get rid of this
person, right? That is the number one
step. It's either fraud or too much
traffic, things like, hey, look at me
like screaming like ban me. And number
one step is get banned. Like that's the
first step. Like how do I get them to go
ban me, right? This could be me
reporting my own account with like 20
other accounts for example. Oh my gosh.
This is crazy.
do that, right? Yeah. So what Joe said
is it's it's So first of all, please
don't go and hassle support people but
Yeah, please don't do that. To be real.
But listen, but there's a difference
between saying, hey, I have a problem.
It's a legitimate problem that causes an
issue versus going like, hey, click on
this thing. I'm never asking a support
staff to click on a link. But I am using
the site like an actual like user and I
go, hey, I can't find this information.
Where do I find it? And I go, oh, I
still can't find it. I really can't
sometimes cuz guess what? My page is
broken.
So I ask them like, hey, could you send
that information for me? That's it's a
lightweight social engineering but I try
to avoid as much as I can. A lot of
times a lot of this blind XSS that I'm
getting nowadays isn't the support staff
being included. It's
me figuring out these companies, how
their processes work and what does it
happen
to get them to look into something I do.
Whether it's like, you know, I put my
credit card number in there but the last
digit is wrong. A lot of times with when
you order something online for example,
they process that manually. They check
for your order manually sometimes
especially if you're banned user.
That's been one of the biggest things,
dude. The number one thing that I used
to do a couple years ago was every
single time
John Boderini and I were sitting at in a
hotel one day Freaking I love I love
John.
Joe, I love I love John. So I look at
him, I go, John, you want to make a
thousand bucks today? He goes, what do
you mean? I go, let's make an order on
this site. And he goes, what do you
mean? I'm like, I'm banned but I bet you
if you put this on this website with a
blind cross site scripting in the
address the second address line, I
promise you that it cross site scripting
will work when we wake up tomorrow. He
looks at me, he goes, bet. We do it. The
next morning we wake up, sure enough it
fired.
No way.
Fast forward fast forward to five years
later. This is this quarter, this last
quarter. I call him again and I go,
John, do you want to make some money,
buddy? He's like, what do you got this
time, Ben?
And I go like, you have an account on
this particular site that I want to use.
I'm banned. Can you just go and do this?
He goes, well, I have a problem with my
account. I'm like, perfect. That's even
better. Can you try this? Sure enough,
tries it. Another blind cross site
scripting starts off.
Wow. It's just getting an understanding
of how these companies work, what
requires them to manually have someone
click on your page and then you assuming
this is the information they're going to
see about you. I'm I'm wondering is is
there any merit to sending your your
cross like say it's like
some sort of logging endpoint or
something like that.
Is there any merit to sending it on a
like a time based basis? Okay, like
every five minutes we're going to send
another one through.
And and because whenever somebody first
opens up the admin portal, you know,
there's always going to be like sort of
like a page paginated list or something
like that. And if you land in that
first, you know, 25 or whatever, then
you might get in that in that front
area. Have you ever thought about that
or any tried anything like that?
done it on purpose because when you do
stuff in the contained manner, it's a
little bit spammy and
it's the last thing I want is but I've
had that happen a couple times. A couple
like fun ones is it asks you for like a
note sometimes. I put in the note, it
doesn't fire. It doesn't fire on their
back end. They copy my note into their
internal net internal app to track and
then it fires, right? I've seen that
happen before. The the typical like in
my email was a fun one. One of the
really cool one was
a website
my password was a blind cross site
scripting payload. No, it was not.
That fired once.
This is just me copy pasting the same
thing for my name, you know, email,
everything and then the the password was
clear text.
Clear text.
No way. That's ridiculous, man.
That one hasn't happened. This was like
eight, nine years ago. This was like no,
yeah,
15, 2016. So six, seven years ago. It
happened. Um
It's just it's just, you know, you never
know, right? You never know. There
there's a couple times where it's fired
off in a engineer's like local machine
because they downloaded everybody's
feedback.
And they were parsing it. That's crazy.
That's so cool. And And so with that, I
kind of want to ask, how do you track
where your payload source was? Because
what what always happens to me when I do
blind XSS is all is all tight, you know,
throw this payload in there and then
I'll get a callback and then I'm like,
[__] where did I put that in a form
somewhere, you know? What do you ask you
a question?
What are you doing for tracking? What
are you using like a cross-site Are you
using like a XSS hunter?
Yeah, I'm just using XSS hunter, normal
XSS hunter on my account.
If you give Oh, okay, that's why. Well,
I don't know how that works. Um I don't
know if truffle allows you to do this.
Can you give it a path?
What What do you mean? Oh, yeah, like a
specific path at the end? Oh, that's
you can set your own your own path. You
only get one path.
Yeah. Oh, so see, this is what I do. I
have my own domain.
If you go to the London event, it was
spammed everywhere. I think they were
like trolling me at some point. Um
So, I started deleting it, but I have a
domain that is not a It's a It's a
cross-site It's a XSS hunter
um JavaScript without the back end of
XSS hunter. So, it's just a It's just a
JavaScript that they have. Yeah. Um and
it it just hooks into a PHP file and
that PHP file is what processes the
entire like when it fires, right? That's
the back end of the PHP file that's like
garbage. It's actually written by
ChatGPT. I [__] you not. Oh my gosh.
the the
the front end of it, I have a HTTP
access rule in a in there that catches
every single path you give and it serves
that JavaScript file if it if it's not
valid. So, my 404 is that JS file that
pops up.
So, when I do a cross-site, you know,
when I do a blind XSS, I do domain.com/
whatever I want to make a note of. So,
the note could be first name in profile.
That's an invalid path. So, when it
fires, it fires with the my JS file and
then it shows me where it's at. But a
lot of times it's also easy to track
because
you know, it's something like your name
or you know, your password and things
like that. It's obvious.
Uh the feedback ones are always the
hardest one to track, but a lot of
companies don't care where it came from
because they know where it came from.
Mm. Yeah.
Right? They they know where they came
from. That's That's really crazy. Yeah,
I mean, I can imagine in scenarios where
developers are like copy and pasting
your data into different applications or
something like that, how you trace it
back to the source. It has to be done on
the company side, I imagine. That one
was a harder one because um yeah, there
was some issues with that one. They'd be
like, oh, well, you messaged our team.
I'm like, no, I didn't message anybody.
They copy-pasted this, dude. And I'm
like, I did not, you know, say this to
them. And it turned out it was a note
that I left. They copied the note into
their internal app and then it fired.
Wow, that that's that's crazy, man. What
a What a crazy hacking story. Yeah, I
know the I know your XSS hunter instance
cuz I know Mr. Same Curry likes to use
it and
I have my own
not mine. That's not mine. That's not
mine. The only person that uses mine is
No, I think that's uh X. That's not
mine. That's XSS. I also use that domain
sometimes.
script cuz I was looking through it and
there's like a bunch of like NahamSec
references in the JS. So, I'm It could
be It could be that
they're using a version of it. I shared
that with everybody in you guys's group.
Like I have no problem with them using
it because it's not something I wrote.
It's also like I also saw Sean using it
in a specific way that I incorporated in
mine. But the biggest thing that I have
is the the PHP file on the back end and
me and Ziad have a um I can't actually
say the name of a bot, but I'll send you
guys the name of the bot later. But we
have a bot that we have I almost said
the name. It could have got me a lot of
trouble.
But uh we have
It's the the name of the bot is the name
of the CEO of the company. Okay.
Okay?
So,
we have a
we have a and then
the the team has also seen this bot when
I screenshotted it for them, but
funny. Uh we have a we have a bot that
uh it just says like, hey everyone on on
Discord, it's at everyone, new blind
cross-site scripting and it gets the URL
from that report and then also links to
the report that I have. It's a text
file. I store it all on my server. It's
password protected, you know, we have to
have a your credentials to log into it.
And I just go look at it and then
analyze it and things like that. That
system is one of the most
[__] up addicting things I've ever
done because when I was getting a lot of
blind cross-site scripting suit, I was
waking up at 5:00 a.m. rolling over and
looking at my phone to see if a new one
popped. And then when you see it pop,
then you can't go back to sleep. Yeah,
it's the same thing. Yeah, dude, I just
set up my own XSS hunter and
I saw how yours was set up cuz I thought
it was like standard. And I really I
really like it cuz I'm going to set up
something to do the same thing with like
the path catch-all and the subdomain
catch-all cuz
it's just a huge
Here's one more thing I got to tell you
guys with like just cross-site scripting
in general. I by default just use my
blind XSS um
payload everywhere.
Because it also helps me track where
these fire.
And then there's been times when
somebody finds some like anomaly
somewhere where they're browsing the
website and it fires.
Like it didn't fire for me,
right? Like on this app and then they
found some weird page that I embedded
and it fired and like I get the
notification now.
And like you go with the mobile app that
sometimes the mobile pages are
different, right? The path on the mobile
page is different than what you saw on
the web app. And then you get a whole
new place of like testing. So, always
always use that for that reason.
Yeah, that makes a lot of sense. And
I want to come back to that CSP thing,
but real quick, I this compares or this
is sort of contrast with what we said
before about using, you know, H1 tags
for your for checking for XSS versus
spraying around all of these blind
cross-site scripting payloads that by
nature of cross-site scripting have to
have some sort of callback, either a JS
or just an external resource callback.
So, how do you balance the two?
So, yes and no. So, when I'm looking for
blind cross-site scripting, Yeah. that
whole
that whole methodology is out the window
because I'm assuming it's going to fire
somewhere, right? When I'm looking for
cross-site scripting,
if it fires, then I go, okay, now how do
I get it to go from from XSS to blind
XSS? But when I
there's a So, how do I explain this?
There's times when I know
most of these companies are
there's behavior you observe on an
application sometimes when you can tell
somebody has reported a cross-site
scripting here because now they're
filtering specific tags, right? But what
they failed to do is look for blind
cross-site scripting now.
So, now my objective is just solely
blind cross-site scripting. And with
blind XSS, you you you don't know. You
just put your payloads in. But then what
becomes interesting with blind XSS is
the assumptions you have to make with
the context of where your payload is
going to end up. So, I'm not just
putting a image tag or a script tag or I
don't know, whatever tag you want to
call it. I'm also thinking about
right No, no, what is the what is the
Where is this going to get indexed on
the back end, right? Because like is it
if if my name is being shown to me on my
profile in in a you know, it's not in a
text area, right? More than likely where
they see it is in an input field or in a
in a in a box in a text area because
they have the ability to edit that,
right? So, that in mind, I have to think
about where that's going to show up,
right? If if I can't put a you know, I
can't if I if I can't close the HTML tag
in an input tag, should I just add an
event handler for an example? Like I
have to think about all these different
things, right? So, you have to think,
where do I put these? Do I put them
before? Do I put them after? Does the
Does the For the input tags, do I put it
before the my actual payload? Do I close
it first? It's all these different
things you got to think about.
So, are you doing that in intelligently?
Like are you thinking, okay, this is
where this is going to Okay, you are.
You're not just using like a polyglot
that has, you know, end text area. Okay,
wow, that's that's really interesting
and you I test it so I test out the
Yeah, I test out the I test out the
theories, right? Like
First of all, like this is a I don't
know if this is unethical, but
it is the reality of it. When you when
your blind cross-site scripting fires,
you have an advantage, Mhm.
right? Because you have the entire DOM
of that page that you can look at. I'm
not saying look for, you know, like ways
to like exploit other vulnerabilities,
but look at how that back end is
created, dude. Are they using a lot of
like text areas? Are they doing a lot of
like What is the way they store data?
And chances are they reuse the same
templates everywhere, right?
So, you have the advantage to know this
is what the back end looks like when
someone fires and you see the you know,
where does my data go? Is it always
going to be, you know, in a title? Is it
going to be a script tag? Like where is
it going to go? You have that advantage.
That That makes a lot of sense. Joel,
swinging back around to the
CSP related question. Go ahead. Sorry.
Yeah, I was going to ask so you
mentioned that for blind XSS you use um
XSS hunter, you know, payload or
whatever. Uh By the way, Sean is the man
to thank for that. We got to give him a
big shout-out.
Huge. I mean,
Yeah, it's been like what, a decade now?
It still works.
Game changer.
Yeah, so crazy. Um but one thing that
that I that has always
sort of puzzled me around how to exploit
that successfully is the whole CSP
aspect, which is that basically like
you're inserting an arbitrary script
tag into a page and even nowadays like
script tags, especially loading from a
URL, often times will just get hit by
you know, blocked by CSP or they just
don't work in general.
Why does it seem to sort of work in the
blind XSS context?
I don't think a lot of these like So,
first of all, like with CSP one is like
I don't know if CSP is there. Like I
don't even know if it's
I don't even know if it's fire on the
one one more time.
Now you know we have been off for a
while, but
No, like with the context of it, like
you you you never So, I don't know if
it's a CSP, I'm never going to see it.
not going to fire. Not my problem
really. I'm not going to dwell on it. A
lot of times I don't think companies,
maybe like Facebook and Google and all
these companies implement CSP on their
internal stuff, but I don't think a lot
of companies care. Their whole thing is
no one's going to see it. It's in our,
you know, it's in our private network.
No one's going to have access to it, so
why bother? Their model is different.
Yeah. So, a lot of times I've never, you
know, I've
any there hasn't been a company that
I've tried blind XSS on, you know, minus
the the fan companies for example. Um
most of those fan companies by at least
like, you know, the big ones that don't
have this problem, right? But with the
the smaller ones there hasn't been a
company where CSP was an issue where I
thought there's a CSP. For some of those
companies when there is a CSP in the
front end, you can assume that there is
going to probably CSP in the back, too.
But that also turns out to be not true
in some cases. So, um
there is a graph I would like to do is
the the the more you [__] around, the
more you find out. Yeah. And honestly,
that's the
great.
That's what I've done with bug bounties,
too, with like blind XSS. The more you
[__] around, the more you find out. So,
that you have nothing to lose to do
that. You have nothing to lose to go
report yourself as as a spam or as a
fraud or, you know, your whatever it is
like reporting for example is a big one
of those things. You're not going to
It's not going to hurt. The only thing
you have is to gain. Worst case is you
lose your account, you make another one,
dude. That that that makes sense. And
then and then from the CSS or CSP front,
you know, I'm wondering if it would make
sense ever to submit more benign blind
XSS payloads like an image tag or like a
like a you know, style tag or or
something that's not necessarily going
to to get caught in the script source
area of the of the CSP. And I know
recently um
uh Gareth Hayes and the PortSwigger team
released a sort of a blind CSS injection
framework where you can exfiltrate, you
know, all of the contents of the inputs
and text areas and stuff like that. Um
do you have any theories on that? Do you
have any experience with non-JS executed
blind XSS?
The the thing with non-JS executed is
sometimes you only have one shot to get
this blind XSS to fire.
That's true.
I think you both know I I like to gamble
once in a while and I would rather just
gamble on the XSS popping up than
worrying about CSP because my only worry
with that is if I get a you know, an
image tag for example to pop up and
whatever it is, right? Then you have to
prove to them that you also have JS to
work.
I don't want to go down that path of
like, you know, having to go through
triage and telling them why this is
vulnerable and then explain to the
engineer why this is vulnerable. Some
companies don't get it. So, I'm going to
gamble the fact that the JavaScript's
going to execute and I have no CSP
issues. And when I if I do, then screw
it. I don't get paid for it and I I just
never know. Yeah, that makes a lot of
sense. Well, that that that was a a
positively intriguing conversation
surrounding blind XSS. I'm very
interested in this and then I'm and and
you know, I I had a phase of like, oh,
I'm finding a lot of blind XSS and then
I stopped looking for it. And then it
it's great to talk with people, you
know, about these sort of
vulnerabilities types cuz it gets you
re-excited for it again. And uh I know
there was a phase where everyone was
kind of putting them in their user agent
and then all of the the freaking uh
you know, WAFs and and stuff started
blocking everybody and it was like, ah,
this is just kind of a pain and it fell
off the the map for me. But uh this is
definitely something I'm going to
reintegrate into my workflow again.
Yeah, for sure, man. I think um I don't
think blind XSS is going to go anywhere
for as long as XSS is around. I don't
think the blind ones are going to go
anywhere. So,
it's still an issue. It's you know, it's
I I just want to like, you know,
preface that if you are looking for XSS,
it's better to just use your own blind
XSS payload than just a vanilla exploit
because it also allows you to track and
everything else. So, it just makes your
life easier. So, just just for the
listeners cuz we we had that all over
the place in that conversation. The
setup that you've got is a a JS file
that exfils data out. You stole that
from the you know, mandatory payload or
whatever. Yeah, XSS Hunter. And then
you've got a PHP file, a custom PHP file
that will parse that out on your own
server, break that into a report, hit a
a Discord callback, and that report is
is, you know, hidden behind basic auth
or whatever, so nobody can just log in
and see the report. Yep.
Wow.
Absolutely. I'll try to see if I can
send you a visual so you can also put it
in the in the bottom right here
somewhere.
Yeah, I would I would I would love to do
that. Um that that that sounds like a
really good system and something that
would be really worthwhile doing. And
then the the other thing that I I wanted
to ask about that specific thing as
customer as far as customizations to the
payload goes, are you exfiltrating
local storage and
uh you know, anything you can you can
get access to beyond the normal payload
or
Um XSS has been trying to push me to do
that a lot more. I haven't done any
local storage stuff. Mine is
send you mine. That'd be cool. But yeah,
mine is
The only thing that I have on there is I
I modify at the bottom I sometimes have
like a you know, an alert sometimes or
also I have it like for mobile apps I
have it dump stuff specific for that
app. But no, the vanilla itself is just
it's just commented out though. Like I
take it out sometimes or I put it back
on or I comment it out, whatever it is.
But just I want to The reason why I want
to
tell you guys that again, use this with
everything that you test for XSS wise
because a it helps you track all your
vulns. So, if you want to go back to
them and see if you can bypass them, you
have that in the context of other
applications, devices. Um there's been a
time where it happened on a device and I
only had one shot at this happening on
the device. Like it popped up on an
actual like physical device. It wasn't a
mobile app. It wasn't It was an actual
like hardware. It popped up on there,
right? And I couldn't modify the
payload, but I guess what? Because it
was my JavaScript file, I could modify
it all I wanted to. That gives you a
huge advantage. The whole thing with XSS
is sometimes you get one shot, you know,
if it happens on a device for example,
you can't modify that, but you can
modify your JavaScript payload. So, keep
that in mind when you do it. That's
awesome. Yeah. The
that was excellent with regards to blind
XSS. I'm hyped about that. And the last
thing that we wanted to cover cuz I know
we're we're into the into the well into
the hour and a half mark here, but you
know, the the intriguing ones always go
a bit long. Um
it we wanted to discuss the going the
extra mile on a bug bounty program to
set up your environment. And this is
something that we talk about on the pod
quite a bit, you know, we we say pay the
extra money to go and get the premium
feature, you know, go through the
rigorous sign up process you need to get
everything set up. Um
could you tell me a little bit about
your experience with that and why that's
such a pivotal part of your your
methodology?
Yeah, I mean a lot of times I going the
extra mile could be the premium, it
could be um so like I know a lot of
people are scared of like, oh, I don't
want to give them my ID cuz what if it
gets hacked? Like I get that. Like I'm
with you, but there's been times when
I've like ID verified myself and that's
gone open up to so much more stuff. I've
sat on like um onboarding calls,
uh I've sat on like QA calls, like the
customer service calls,
uh you name it, dude. Like it helps. The
other thing is like it also goes as far
as like customizing your um instance,
right? Like
uh some of these companies allow you to
like configure everything. Yeah, or
styling everything. And
you know, there's all a lot of these The
more you give them, unfortunately,
that's the reality of it. The reason
First of all, there's two things. One,
they want your money or they want your
data.
Right? Like they want your money because
you want to purchase something, so you
pay them, they open up more stuff.
Sometimes it's expensive, so you can't
pay for it. Um you can ask the company,
they'll give it to you. But then the
other one is like sometimes they want
you to verify. Like Airbnb's a big one.
You can't be a host without giving them
your ID and stuff. A lot of hackers stop
at that phase because they don't want,
you know, what if my money gets hacked?
I don't want to have my information. I
don't want to have my social. But you
have to do those things cuz it opens up
a lot of more stuff. Um but also keep in
mind of like again, I want to say the
whole like the ROI of your time. If you
are if a company is maybe giving you
1,000 for a critical, maybe not worth it
unless you're like,
you know, fast instead of you know,
you're going to maybe go for a quantity
of criticals, then that's that is worth
it. But if a company is like 25k max or
even 10k max, right? That is still worth
it. That is the return in your time. You
know, there was a company that I hacked
on that required me to
send them a bunch of letters. Like I had
to actually ship letters to them. And I
spent like 3 days at the post office
doing that, dude.
Oh my gosh. I did it and it ended up
being a really good bug, right? Um my
tax documents right now every year I get
them as a script tag inside of it. Like
because I went into this company that
does my taxes on a bug bounty program. I
paid them to do my taxes one year. I did
all that stuff, right? I've gone as far
as like opening retirement accounts
with particular companies.
That's amazing.
So, like it's not that I'm like, you
know, I'm trying to I think about it,
go, oh, I'm going to retire I'm going to
open up a retirement account, right? Who
should I do it with? I think about these
companies that are big. Do they have a
bug bounty program that I can also test
out?
Right? There's also you want to invest
money. Like all these different things.
Like think about it. Like it's always
the mentality of how you are a hacker,
too. I'll I'll never forget this time
where you and I were collaborating on a
on a target where you could open up a
credit card with this target. And uh you
you gave me access to your to your
credit card. You're like, here, just log
into my account.
card? Yeah. I had their most expensive
credit card. I had their checking
account.
And like two other services with them,
too, dude. I didn't open up their most
credit card cuz I wanted it. It was
because of that event, dude.
Yeah. And and I really wanted to see
what that company did. And I was like I
was like, dude, why the heck are you
doing this? And but at the same time I
was telling you like about all of these
you know, benefits I was getting from
signing up for these you know, credit
cards and then you know, doing the point
hacking thing. And you're like, bro, you
know, if we find one bug, you're going
to get so much more value out of this
than all of these like credit card
hacking points things you're doing.
maximum thing you pay the the maximum
you pay for a credit card is like $700 a
year a year. Yeah, 700 is probably the
one that I've been paid the most. The
maximum bounty can get from a company
that size is what? Like 15, 20k?
Yeah, for sure. At least.
Right. So, I mean also like the the
checking account is free, so who cares?
The credit card I wanted that credit
card at some point and then the program
pushed me, but those are just like
things to think about, right? Like if
you're making an order with a company
that's a bug bounty program, think of
like, oh, what else can I do with this?
Um
So, yeah, that's the the biggest thing
to it, man. Like you just got to think
about like I'm going to make this
decision for my personal life.
Obviously, don't base it all on your bug
bounty experience, but if you have the
option and you think, you know, you're
deciding between two companies one has a
bug bounty program, I'm going to go with
that one since I can also test it out.
Yeah. Yeah, see see you can test it and
also just because you know it's going to
be more secure as well, you know, like
people are in there testing on it every
day, so there's there's value to that.
Um
Ben, dude, this has been legendary, man.
Thank you so much for coming on and
sharing all this knowledge and and I'm
so glad to see the, you know, completed
rise from from the low lows to the high
highs after after doing, you know, half
a mil in bug bounty and really crushing
the video scene and seeming much more
happy and and stable and uh it's really
it's really inspiring, man.
Yeah, of course and kudos to you guys
for, you know, making such a good
podcast and staying consistent and
bringing, you know, so many amazing
guests. Yeah. I thank you guys for
having me and I'm excited to see what
else you guys put out. For sure. Thanks,
man. Absolutely, dude. Yeah. That's the
pod. Peace.